♪ Here we are going far ♪
♪ to save all that we love ♪
♪ If we give all we’ve got ♪
♪ we will make it through ♪
♪ Here we are like a star ♪
♪ shining bright
on your world today ♪
♪ Make evil go away ♪
♪ Code Lyoko we’ll
withstand it all ♪
♪ Code Lyoko be there
when you call ♪
♪ Code Lyoko we
will stand real tall ♪
♪ Code Lyoko
stronger after all ♪
(SNORING)
(BARKS)
Hey!
What are you
doing here, huh?
(YAPPING)
You dumb dog!
Wait ’til I get
my hands on you!
I’ll get you this time,
you mangy mutt!
Yeah! Way to go, Kiwi!
(BARKING)
Jeremie!
You mind telling me
what you’re doing
outside at this hour?
And that, huh!
What's that supposed to be?
(TROMBONE)
If I’d have had more time,
I could’ve done the eyes better.
I hope this will teach you
a lesson, Jeremie.
I don’t understand.
A model student like you?
You should be ashamed.
Uh…yes, sir.
-What did he say?
-Well, tell us!
He gave me detention
for the whole week of vacation.
Cool!
He really let you have it!
As punishments go,
you’re a champion!
I’m sure we couldn’t have
done better than that!
Anyway, XANA won’t get
any vacation this time.
Am I dreaming,
or does Jeremie look happy
to be punished
for the vacatoin?
Yeah, it sure is weird.
You’d almost think
he did what he did
because he wanted
to be punished.
I don’t get it.
Me neither.
And who’s this XANA
he was talking about?
Herb is right. It’s even
weirder than weird.
And I’m gonna find out
just what’s going on.
Huh? What are you
gonna do?
Don’t you have to leave
with your dad after school?
A little change of schedule.
Daddy, can I talk
to you for a minute?
But, Sissi dear,
I am very busy.
It won’t take long.
Well, you see, there’s this girl I know
whose grades aren’t very good,
and the best thing for her
would be to study over the vacation,
but she’s supposed to
go to see her grandparents.
I see. And who is this--?
Shh! I’m coming to that!
She knows that when she
gets to her grandparents’ house,
she won’t feel like studying,
so what do you think she should do?
She needs your advice as a principal!
Well, my advice would be
to give up her vacation
and stay home and study
for her own good.
What’s this girl’s name?
Perhaps I could talk to her…
You just did, daddy! It’s me!
Thank you for the advice!
I promise to study hard!
Kiss grandma and grandpa for me!
You get to go and see your parents
at the other end of the planet,
Yumi’s off for a vacation
in the mountains, and what do I get?
A whole week of math tutoring.
If they think they can make
a good student
out of you in one week,
well, I say good luck to them.
It sounds like mission
impossible if you ask me.
You’re sure you can manage
on your own without us?
No sweat, and if XANA
leaves me alone,
I’ll be able to work on
Aelita’s materialization.
Oh, don’t worry.
He’s not gonna be alone.
I’m staying at school, too,
and I’ll look after him.
I’ll be his guardian angel.
Wow, Jeremie, are you lucky.
Alright, young man.
You think this wall’s
gonna clean itself?
Get to work NOW!
(CACKLING)
Go on, go on.
Laugh while you
still can, young lady.
Your father told me
to monitor your studying,
and that's what I intend to do!
Okay, now.
Get to work
and clean that up.
I don’t know why,
but all of a sudden,
my math tutoring
doesn’t seem all that bad.
Come on, you can do
better than that!
A little more elbow grease!
Keep scrubbing.
Go on, you can do it.
How’s that math problem?
Making any progress solving it?
I sure hope so!
Well, I’m a little bit stuck here.
Maybe if I gave
Jeremie some help.
My father always says that
manual labor is good for the brain!
Huh, I guess all kids
aren’t lazy, after all.
Good idea, Sissi.
Stay there.
I’ll go and get you a sponge.
Oh, what a shame
to have to wipe all that off.
I guess I’m not the first one
to recognize your talent.
It’s really well done.
A work of art.
By the way, did you do it
all by yourself?
Or did your friend XANA
help you a little, huh?
(SINISTER MUSIC)
I overheard you talking
to the other kids about XANA.
Is she your girlfriend?
Maybe I know her.
Come on, Jeremie, tell me.
XANA’s the name
of a rock group.
But with all the junk
that you listen to,
there’s no way you could
possibly know them.
What do you think I am?
An idiot or something?
Uh, you said it, not me.
Here. Since you
volunteered to help me.
It’s time I took a break.
A little more elbow grease!
Go on, keep scrubbing!
You can do it!
Go on, you can do better than that!
(CLEARS THROAT)
Oh, I ache all over. I swear.
I'm telling you, I'd have
never thought it was possible
to be this sore.
It even hurts to blink!
Sissi, you should go to sleep.
Are you kidding? I can’t.
What if Jeremie
tries something tonight!
Oh, yeah? What?
I don't know,
but he's up to something.
I'm sure of that.
And I’m almost sure that
this XANA is in on it.
Tonight’s the night.
I’m going to play super spy.
At last, I’m gonna find out the secret
of Jeremie and his weird friends!
I know I’m on the right track,
but I need the computer in the lab
to check out the figures.
I’m gonna head over to the factory.
You should go to bed, Jeremie.
XANA seems to be stable.
I don’t feel any pulsations.
And you know
it’s not the end of the world
if I stay virtual one more day.
That’s fine for you,
but if you don’t come soon,
I’m gonna have to spend my vacation
with Sissi and Jim.
I’ll never survive.
Jeremie, thank you.
Thank you for everything you’re doing for me.
That’s okay.
(CRASHING)
(COUGHING)
Aaaah!
Now, don’t try to tell me
that you were sleepwalking
because I’ve been
working here for 20 years,
and I’ve heard that story about…
Jim, something awful has happened!
Have a look! In there!
Huh?
Looks like there was a hurricane in there.
This had better not be your doing.
But the smoke! It’s disappeared!
That’s weird. Not even a trace.
It’s XANA.
Don’t even think about leaving this room.
Tomorrow, I’m calling your parents.
You’ve got some explaining to do.
I wouldn’t want to be in your shoes.
Aelita! Come in, please. Hurry.
We’ve got a big problem.
You’re not the only one.
XANA’s woken up.
But I don’t know which tower he’s activated.
But the pulsation converge in this direction.
It’s even worse than I thought.
The spilled bottles contain
an extremely poisonous substance.
If the computer is right,
the gas can even be deadly
in cases of extended inhalation.
Get up, young man. Time to face the music.
Huh?
Jeremie!
W-What’s happening? Where am I?
I can’t see. I’m totally out of it!
What’s going on?
(SCREAMS)
Jim! Over there! Smoke! With arms!
This has got to be contagious.
What’s all this about smoke, anyway?
Come on, I don’t see any--
Waaaah!
Bingo.
Aelita, I found it.
37 degrees south in the forest area.
Okay, I’m on my way.
But I’m nowhere near it,
and I’m gonna need some help.
I know three volunteers who will be happy
to cut their vacation short and help.
You’ll soon learn that mathematics
is actually quite easy, young man.
All you need is a sense of logic,
a little bit of common sense,
and, of course, if you have good
concentration skills, and if you have…
“S.O.S XANA--Jeremie.”
…analysis, that will help as well,
but I assure you, if you apply yourself,
it’s not at all complicated.
Hey, come and have a look at this, Charlie.
What is it?
Wow, that’s incredible!
What is that, kid?
Uh…it’s a…
Looks like a skeleton!
Yeah, that’s right, but, uh,
don’t you see anything strange?
Your skeleton is moving.
Oh, that’s Kiwi!
Kiwi’s my dog.
You do know that dogs are only
allowed in the luggage compartment?
Well, yeah sure, uh…
I don’t know what happened!
He was supposed to stay here…
with my grandma, but…
Mhmm.
(CELL PHONE RINGS)
Oh, it’s gram!
We were just talking about you!
What are you talking about, Odd?
It’s me, Jeremie.
Yes, of course I know it’s you, gram!
I’m sorry.
I know you’ve told me a hundred times
that you don’t like me to call you gram!
Yeah, okay.
I’m on my way. Right.
I’ll bring back the dog.
Bye, gram.
We should have left over two hours ago.
You know how much she loves that dress.
I don’t even know
what dress she’s talking about.
I’m coming! I’ll be down in two seconds!
Yeah, I doubt that.
You’re going to laugh,
darling, when I tell you…
No, I don’t really feel like laughing.
Have you noticed someone
is missing in the back seat?
Oh, no!
(COUGHING)
Over here. Hurry up!
Jeremie, I’m coming into the forest area now.
Yumi, Ulrich, and Odd
should be there very soon.
Be careful, Aelita.
There are bound to be monsters around there.
I better go back to the school.
Jim and Sissi might be in trouble.
I’ve got to warn them.
Help! Help us!
Help!
It’s not use. We’re finished.
No, no. We’re not finished.
Be brave, now.
Jeremie can’t be far away.
He’ll help us out of this!
Jeremie? That’s pretty reassuring.
It’s nice to know that the closest thing
to Bruce Willis is coming to the rescue.
Sissi? Jim? Where are you?
We’ll cut across through
the boiler room. It's faster.
(COUGHING)
Through the park.
Jeremie!
Jim and Sissi are still inside.
We’ve got to find them.
I’ll go.
Ulrich, wait!
Yumi, the factory.
You’ve got to go and help Aelita.
Hang on, Jeremie.
Odd, you got here in the nick of time.
Where’s Ulrich?
I only stayed at school to try and find out
the secret of Jeremie and his friends
because the truth is that I’ve been wanting
to be part of their group for ages,
but it seems so hopeless.
Do you understand what I mean?
Huh? No.
All I understand is that
there’s no ventilation in here.
We’re gonna run out of oxygen soon.
I’d better stop talking then, right?
Okay. I can take a hint.
A strange and toxic smoke
whose origins are unknown.
The elderly and children
are advised to remain indoors.
Odd.
Help me get over to the computer.
(COUGHING)
And get ready to dive in.
Stop looking at me! Come on!
There’s no time to lose!
Transfer Yumi.
Transfer Odd.
Scanner Yumi.
Scanner Odd.
Virtualization.
Where do we go now?
The activated tower is over this way.
Hi, Aelita!
Have you seen any monsters?
Not yet.
Guess you didn’t look very hard!
Ulrich, do you copy?
How’s it going?
Still nothing.
I’ve been through most of the building.
Ulrich, get out of there.
You can’t stay in that smoke any longer.
It's too dangerous.
And they may be outside already.
I-I’ll try one last room. Then I’ll go.
(COUGHING)
Jim!
Jim! Sissi! Are you in there?
Ulrich, get out right now!
Ulrich! Come on!
What’s going on!
Ulrich, answer me!
Look, I don’t want
to rush you, my friends,
but it’s getting kind of urgent here.
What about us?
What do you think we’re doing, huh?
Getting a suntan?
Odd, watch out.
You okay, Yumi?
No broken bones yet.
Take good care of Aelita.
There. You see, Sissi?
I told you he’d come and rescue us.
What the…Ulrich!
He came for me!
Oh, he came to save me!
It’s just like I always dreamed!
The only way to access the tower
is via a tree bridge.
But it happens to be behind the monsters,
and so you’re gonna have to
find a way around them.
I might have an idea
for blocking the monsters.
You take care of Aelita.
Laser flash!
Yumi! If she gets hit one more time…
Jeremie!
Welcome to Earth, Yumi.
Hey, look. A cell phone!
Now we’ll be able to
call for help.
Jim, is that you, huh?
Jeremie!
Where are you? And Ulrich?
Jeremie, we really need help.
We’re starting to run out of oxygen in here.
Oh, no!
Jim, what’s happening?
Jim!
Odd, hurry up!
Well, what do we do now?
You take care of the monsters.
(CELESTIAL HUMMING)
Hey, you!
That’s right. You.
Laser flash!
Let’s hope it’s not too late.
Aelita, hurry up!
Return to the past now.
I don’t understand why you insist on
getting punished with
detention again, Jeremie.
Come on, XANA’s not
gonna reactivate this soon.
You could get yourself a short vacation.
Not as long as Aelita stays virtual.
And this time, to tell you the truth,
considering what we’ve painted,
Jim can’t be too angry!
Come to think of it,
I’m gonna stick around.
Anything is better than another one
of Mrs. Schmitt’s math lessons.
Even Jim.
(BARKING)
Get back here!
CLOSED CAPTIONING PROVIDED BY
REDDIT.COM/R/CODELYOKO